Hello and welcome back.
In the last lecture, we saw how MCB tools can be used to perform actions on internal
applications and API.
In this lecture, we will add a resource to our MCP server.
MCP resource is a static data source that the MCP server can expose to the client and
it can be used to provide additional context to the LLM model.
A typical example for MCP resource is a databases schema.
The MCP server can expose the databases schema as a resource.
The user can load the databases schema because it's provided or exposed from the MCP server
and then immediately the user is able to ask the model to write SQL queries based on
the provided databases schema.
At the code level, adding a resource to the MCP server is very simple and straightforward.
It should look similar to adding an MCP tool.
So we create a Python method and we add a decorator to indicate that this is an MCP resource.
We define a resource URI to the decorator and this URI is used by the MCP client to access
the resource.
The implementation is literally straightforward.
We just literally read a file or the resource that we want to expose and then we return
that content or that file to the MCP client.
So now we are back to cloud desktop and the available MCP resources can be found under
the plus sign and then we add from Contentful MCP server and then I'm going to pick up
the databases schema.
Now at this point the MCP client has loaded the databases schema from the MCP server so
we should be able to ask questions like can you explain the databases schema in shortest
statement.
And the model started to load and read the databases schema and try to break it down for
me.
Okay, I hope that this lecture has been informative for you and I will see you in the next
one.
[BLANK_AUDIO]